MICHAEL BEAUJEAN

Brooklyn, NY | beaujean.io | 914.589.7527

Summary

Over the past 5 years, I've worked with global brands, startups and creative agencies to develop elegant, engaging experiences on the web.

Skills

JavaScript, React, Webpack, APIs, HTML/CSS, SVG, Wordpress, PHP, D3.js, Highcharts, js, Git, Sketch, Illustrator, Photoshop

Experience

OppenheimerFunds

Front End Developer / May 2018 - present

I worked on a development team embedded within the digital design team to craft interactive web experiences. I also worked with the optimization team to develop A/B tests to improve UX across OppenheimerFunds.com.

The Wall Street Journal

Lead Developer / Nov 2016 – May 2018

I lead a creative development team to scope, engineer and launch the Wall Street Journal's marketing presence on the web. Reported to a creative director and worked directly with WSJ/Dow Jones's marketing and technical teams.

Front End Developer / Sept 2015 – Nov 2016

I collaborated with developers, creative directors, designers and copywriters to build digital experiences for WSJ/Dow Jones.

Outer Places

Web Developer / Oct 2014 – Sept 2015

I built, optimized and maintained OuterPlaces.com's v2.0 relaunch, while collaborating with design, editorial, SEO and marketing teams.

SMAKK Studios

Web Developer / Aug 2014 - Sept 2014

A freelance project doing front-end/CMS development for a client's website re-design.

Education

Iona College

Bachelor's Degree in Mass Communications/Media Studies / Class of 2009

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive / Feb 2014 - May 2014

I completed General Assembly's 3-month intensive program learning Ruby on Rails full stack web development.